
    <rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[王孟源有新回复]]></title>
    <atom:link href="https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[王孟源有新回复 (https://github.com/taizihuang/wmyblog)]]></description>
    <generator>Github</generator>
    <webMaster>Taizi Huang</webMaster>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>04-22 16:07 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>5</ttl>
    <item>
    
    
    <title><![CDATA[【美國】海湖莊園抄家事件幕後的美國政治鬥爭 | 後註九]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[後註九 <br><br>----<br><br>三名Black Empowerment幹部（亦即追求真正種族平等的黑人反霸主義運動，當年的Black Panther是其中一個分支）剛剛被逮捕起訴（參見&lt;a href="https://www.postguam.com/the_globe/nation/black-activists-charged-with-role-in-russian-propaganda-scheme/article_1157603c-df27-11ed-9dcb-97a77a9b6df7.htmll"&gt;&lt;span style="color:blue"&gt;《Black activists charged with role in Russian propaganda scheme》&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;），罪行是和一個俄國NGO合辦了一場網絡座談會，並且膽敢在會中批評美國挑動俄烏戰爭，所用的罪名是“conspiracy to defraud the United States and impersonating agents of foreign governments”。這裏最奇怪的是，號稱對種族運動非常熱心的民主黨系主流媒體，竟然一句話都不提，難免讓人懷疑所謂的“民主”、“自由”、“平等”，其實正是一個充滿著專制、奴役和歧視的體系利用特權所創造出來的謊話，只不過他們的撒謊是無孔不入、極度無恥罷了。&lt;/p&gt;
]]></description>
    <author><![CDATA[王孟源部落格]]></author>
    <pubDate>2023-04-22 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2304220000</guid>
    <link>https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog/html/177165976.html#2304220000</link>
    </item>
    <item>
    
    
    <title><![CDATA[【戰略】【國際】對俄烏戰爭的新觀察 | 上善若水水利万物]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[有一新闻不同寻常卫星空拍图发现环克里米亚半岛西海岸线海滩上建了大量强固工事、反坦克壕还加上了岸防炮摆上龙牙但是乌克兰并没有制空权、制海权和大规模两栖登陆战能力有什么必要再远离可能战场上的海岸线建筑大量反两栖登陆强固工事，唯一可能得解释是俄罗斯用来防范北约，但是北约又是什么原因要入侵这里呢？加上最近得泄密事件据说有100多页机密文档被在泄漏出来，华盛顿邮报以及其他主媒宣称找到了五角大楼泄密的嫌疑人，一名21岁的空军国民警卫队成员。文件本身是真的，但是它是CIA内部文件，只有很少数的高级人员有权限接触，一般美军基地的人员不可能有权限接触到，美媒报导的这个说法很有可能是情报部门指示主媒杜撰出来以引导舆论。 <br><br>----<br><br>]]></description>
    <author><![CDATA[王孟源部落格]]></author>
    <pubDate>2023-04-16 07:19:00 +0800</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2304160719</guid>
    <link>https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog/html/177266891.html#2304160719</link>
    </item>
    <item>
    
    
    <title><![CDATA[【戰略】【國際】從SWIFT制裁俄國，看中國的對應之道 | 上善若水水利万物]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[鲁拉访问中国鲁拉率庞大访问团访问中国看来天下苦美元霸权很久了，鲁拉一来就提为什么不能使用其他货币呢？新开银行行长罗赛芙和鲁拉长期合作在巴西地区反美，希望巴西全国人民脱离贫困这两位总统以前还是左翼游击队员后来被美国的代理人陷害坐牢看到这巴西总统句话感觉先生的预测正确率提高了 <br><br>----<br><br>]]></description>
    <author><![CDATA[王孟源部落格]]></author>
    <pubDate>2023-04-16 06:54:00 +0800</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2304160654</guid>
    <link>https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog/html/171980706.html#2304160654</link>
    </item>
    <item>
    
    
    <title><![CDATA[【軍事】從美國看閲兵 | AAB]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[Shifting Biases cont.Going back on articles that are less recent and arguably more prone to belittling China, the listed writers are still active in TWZ with the notable difference of very much reduced China coverage.China’s J-20 Stealth Fighter Will Likely Look Like This At Its Air Show Debut (thedrive.com)This linked article for instance has comments on the J-20 that haven't aged well in view of recent developments, but the writer for this piece has only written on China very sparingly in the past 2 years, and only on matters tangentially related to the PLA or its weapons (e.g. the meteorological balloon).Disregarding the matter of fields of expertise, embarrassment over 'eating crow' might be a notable impediment to the changing of prejudices and attitudes. While military observers might hold themselves to relatively stricter standards with technical details and material fact, it would still be hard to have individual writers/people openly contradict previously expressed/held opinions.This would go against the suggestion that CGTN or another Chinese media agency absorb the wave of media workers that a British implosion/BBC restructuring would bring, wouldn't it? After all, it would be quite difficult to not be conditioned to at least partially subscribe to propaganda you propagate. Even converts would likely need to face the risk of reputational damage if they go against their previous stances. <br><br>----<br><br>]]></description>
    <author><![CDATA[王孟源部落格]]></author>
    <pubDate>2023-04-15 19:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2304151948</guid>
    <link>https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog/html/129820465.html#2304151948</link>
    </item>
    <item>
    
    
    <title><![CDATA[【軍事】從美國看閲兵 | AAB]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[Shifting BiasesThose two TWZ articles were certainly great examples of a shift in tone and attitude, and they also seem to highlight how changes in attitudes (towards e.g. China/PLA/PLAAF/etc.) are likely going to be organisational rather than personal. I have a question that relates to the suggestion here【美國】【國際】2022年國際局勢的回顧與展望 - 王孟源的部落格 - udn部落格to incorporate English-speaking media talent a la RT (3rd paragraph under subtitle UK).Those two articles were submitted under a Thomas Newdick, who started writing for TWZ only in 2020, and one of them by Andreas Rupprecht, an oft-cited OSINT/Chinese military aviation expert, and most of their coverage/social media presence had been positive-neutral at the very least regarding the PLA and its modernisation, with very little of the condescension and derision that comes with the more 'American patriotic' articles that typically appear on TWZ. It would be better characterised as 'consistently rational (unbiased against China) writers being allowed more coverage on the publication' rather than 'anti-China writers changing their ways'.(TBC) <br><br>----<br><br>]]></description>
    <author><![CDATA[王孟源部落格]]></author>
    <pubDate>2023-04-15 19:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2304151943</guid>
    <link>https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog/html/129820465.html#2304151943</link>
    </item>
    <item>
    
    
    <title><![CDATA[【基礎科研】【戰略】恐龍的起源 | Taizi Huang]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[王先生，后注三的source是《表亲与cousins》(https://blog.udn.com/MengyuanWang/108908819) <br><br>----<br><br>]]></description>
    <author><![CDATA[王孟源部落格]]></author>
    <pubDate>2023-04-15 12:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2304151205</guid>
    <link>https://taizihuang.github.io/wmyblog/html/118448301.html#2304151205</link>
    </item>
    </channel></rss>
    